Elsewhere in the course, we established a
relationship between the Person.CountryRegion
and Person.StateProvince tables, with the
CountryRegionCode column, the primary key
in the Person.CountryRegion table, being linked
to the foreign key field of the same field name
in the Person.StateProvince table. Let's
look at one aspect of this relationship
from a practical standpoint. I still have the
design of the Person.StateProvince table open,
and I am going to select the Table
Designer menu and the Relationships option.
Then, I will select the relationship we created,
and I just want you to notice one setting:
the Enforce Foreign Key Constraint option
is set to Yes. That is the default setting
when a relationship is created. This setting
enforces a concept called referential integrity,
which ensures that a primary key value exists in
a relationship before the corresponding foreign
key value is allowed. That is the technical
definition of referential integrity. Let me
now explain this through the lens of looking at
the Person.CountryRegion table. I've closed this
Foreign Key Relationships window and then return
the top 1000 rows from the Person.CountryRegion
table. Let me now pose a question: Should a
country region code be defined in this table
before it is allowed anywhere else? In other
words, what do you think would happen if in this
Person.StateProvince table, a CountryRegionCode
was entered that did not exist here? As you can
imagine, we would have a problem because we
would have no idea what the CountryRegionCode
should represent. This situation causes orphaned
records, which are records in a foreign key table
with no matches in a primary key table.
Enforcing referential integrity ensures
this does not happen, that a primary key
value must exist for it to be allowed in
any foreign key table. In other words,
only CountryRegionCodes that exist here
are allowed in any entity to which this
has a relationship using this field.